Sharath Pandeshwar

Self Explorer

raosharat@gmail.com

Summary

About Me: I want to enable simpler and more productive Living using Technology. I am willing to tear down walls, build bridges, and light fires. I have some experience, lots of energy, a bit of that "vision thing" and I'm not afraid to start from the beginning.

Mission: Using Technology to build tools that enable simpler, more productive Living.

Specialties: Technology, Leadership, Management and Communications.

Education

M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication Engineering, 2004 - 2008

Viveka Junior College-Kota

PUC, Science, 2002 - 2004

SSRS Hattiangady

SSLC, General Studies, 1998 - 2002

Experience

Ideator and Conceptualist at InfiniTec

April 2013 - Present (6 months)

Identify problems, conceptualize technological solution to solve the problem and implement the same.

Trainer at QuanTech Origin

March 2010 - Present (3 years 7 months)

Quantitative Aptitude and Logical Reasoning Trainer for Campus Placement Entrance Exams for QuanTech Origin. Trained in several colleges like Atria Institute of Technology, DBIT, SKIT, CMRIT, RIT, CIT, CiTech, SSEC, KNSIT, NCET and several other Colleges across Karnataka. Wide exposure to all topics under Math and Logical reasoning.

1 recommendation available upon request

Chief Operating Officer at QuanTech Origin

March 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 3 months)

Responsible for day to day Operations and new business development at QuanTech Origin.

3 recommendations available upon request

Assistant Area Governor-Area B3, District 82 at Toastmasters International

January 2012 - June 2012 (6 months)

Responsible for developing and directing programs for new club development, club rescue efforts, club membership promotion, and membership retention for the Area B3 of Toastmasters District D82.

Tail Twister at Lions Club of Bangalore Jayamahal

July 2011 - June 2012 (1 year)

Instill enthusiasm and good fellowship in the meetings, and to keep harmony in Lions Club meetings.

R&D Engineer at IBM

July 2008 - February 2012 (3 years 8 months)

Wide exposure to various facets of VLSI Design. At IBM-ISL, handled Foundry PDK Testing and Foundry IP Maintenance and was also main point of contact for Automation.

1 recommendation available upon request

President at Blue Expression Toastmasters Club

July 2011 - December 2011 (6 months)

Handled Leadership and Management at Blue Expression Toastmasters Club. Was responsible for installing processes and a sense of Vision and Spirit. Initiated several major Activities like Newsletter, Joint Meetings, PR Campaigns, Quality Campaigns and Training Programs. Also involved the Club is several CSR initiatives and represented the Club at several District Level Programs.

For Detailed Report: http://www.blueexpression.org/Pandeshwar_Report.pdf

4 recommendations available upon request

Vice President Public Relations at Blue Expression Toastmasters Club

November 2010 - June 2011 (8 months)

Was responsible for Communications and Public Relations at the Blue Expression Toastmasters Club. Initiated the process of branding the Club through several Social Media tools.

1 recommendation available upon request

Founder and CEO at BrainChild Marketing

September 2010 - June 2011 (10 months)

Brave and ground-breaking attempt to redefine marketing by introducing new and innovative media for Targeted Marketing.

Treasurer at Lions Club of Bangalore Jayamahal

July 2010 - June 2011 (1 year)

Budgeting and Financial Management for the Lionistic Year 2010-2011.

Secretary at Lions Club of Bangalore Jayamahal

July 2009 - June 2010 (1 year)

Responsible for Management, Operations and Communication for the Lionistic Year 2009-2010.

Intern at IBM-ISL

January 2008 - March 2008 (3 months)

Web Portal Project.

1 recommendation available upon request

Skills & Expertise

Organizational Leadership

Program Management

Entrepreneurship

Marketing Communications

Team Leadership

Team Building

Budgets

Leadership

Management

Public Speaking

Team Management

 \mathbf{C}

Training

Operations Management

Time Management

Perl Automation

Android Development

XML

HTML

JavaScript

jQuery Mobile

PhoneGap

Public Relations

Teamwork

Projects

Nexus-Toastmasters Cricket Tournament

November 2011 to January 2012

Members: Sharath Pandeshwar, Hrishikesh Kumar, Dr Vikram Venkateswaran, Geetha Prasanna

First ever Cricket Tournament organized for Toastmasters in Bangalore. We have the credit of bringing Cricket to Toastmasters in India. The scope involved complete project management aspects and selling the idea of playing cricket. It climaxed in the tennis ball, Inter Toastmasters Club Cricket Tournament that was held on January 29th 2012 at Veterinary College Grounds Hebbal. 19 Teams including 21 Clubs participated and event was witnessed by more than 250 people. The event was a huge success. For more details please visit:

http://nexus82.weebly.com/first-season-report.html

NSN Wordly-Wise Toastmasters Club

January 2012 to June 2012

Members: Sharath Pandeshwar, Himanshu Awasthi, Raveendra Bhat, Dr Vikram Venkateswaran, Arati Udupi

Setting up and establishing 'Wordly-Wise Toastmasters Club' at Nokia Siemens Network in Manyata Tech Park. The project involved Conception, Strategic and Financial planning, Publicity initiatives and Project execution. It all culminated in successful chartering of the Club on:

My role in the project was of Sponsor, Mentor and Facilitator.

Aptitude for Jobs-Android Application

January 2013 to Present

Members: Sharath Pandeshwar, Vighnesh Shanbhag, Abhilasha Singh

Most comprehensive and most appropriate collection of Quantitative Aptitude and Logical Reasoning questions in one Android Application.

QuoteMaster-Android Application

May 2013 to Present

Members: Sharath Pandeshwar, Abhilasha Singh, Vighnesh Shanbhag

A tool that enables public speakers to save quotes and one liners according to categories/tags and retrieve them at the moment of need.

HowLong - Hybrid Mobile Application

June 2013 to Present

Members:Sharath Pandeshwar

An Application to track important milestones in terms of number of days past and number of days since.

Technicalities: Hybrid mobile application Development with Jquery, Jquery Mobile, PhoneGap and HTML5.

Certifications

Diploma in C Programming and C++

Manipal Institute of Computer Education July 2004

Android 4.0 Application Development

Java Learning Center November 2012

Organizations

Lions Club of Bangalore Jayamahal

Member

October 2008 to Present

Lions Club of Bangalore Jayamahal, affiliated to Lions Clubs International is an organization which aims to meet the needs of communities on a local and global scale.

Toastmasters International

Member

September 2010 to Present

Toastmasters International (TI) is a nonprofit educational organization that operates clubs worldwide for the purpose of helping members improve their communication, public speaking and leadership skills. Through its thousands of member clubs, Toastmasters International offers a program of communication and leadership projects designed to help men and women learn the arts of speaking, listening, and thinking.

Honors and Awards

Advanced Communicator Bronze

Toastmasters International

March 2012

Awarded 'Advanced Communicator Bronze' for Public Speaking specialization in Story Tellling and Entertainment Speeches.

Advance Leader Bronze

Toastmasters International

January 2012

For having successfully fulfilled criteria for Advanced Leader Bronze.

Leadership Excellence Award

Toastmasters International

February 2012

For successful completion of High Performance Leadership Project.

Competent Communicator Award

Toastmasters International

April 2011

Awarded 'Competent Communicator' by Toastmasters International for completing ten Speech Projects.

Competent Leader Award

Toastmasters International

April 2011

Awarded 'Competent Leader' by Toastmasters International for completing ten Leadership Projects.

Outstanding Toastmaster for the Year 2010-2011

Blue Expression Toastmasters Club

June 2011

Multiple Best Lion Secretary Award

Multiple Lions District 324D

May 2011

Best Lion Secretary Award in Multiple District 324D for the year 2009-10.

Multiple Best Treaurer Award

Multiple District 324D6-Lions Club International February 2012

'Multiple Best Treaurer Award' for Multiple District 324D6.

Best Lion Secretary Award

Lions District 324D6 July 2010

Best Lion Secretary Award in Lions District 324D6 for the year 2009-10.

XL District Gloden Award

Lions District 324D6 July 2011

XL District Gloden Award for Treasurer in Lions District 324D6 for the year 2010-11.

Lion of the Year (2009-2010)

Lions Club of Bangalore Jayamahal June 2010

Lion of the year at LCB Jayamahal for the year 2009-2010.

Honors and Awards

Others:

Selected for Tata Jagriti Yatra-2012. [Turned it down. After all this what the heck?]

Recommended for 'Emerging Lion 2013 Award' (Pan India level) [Turned down]

Volunteered as Trainer for Ryla-2011.

Certified on 'Negotiation Skills', 'Assertiveness' and 'Winning Teams' from Siksha Corporate Consulting. Certified in 'Seven Habits of Highly Effective People' from IBM Stepping Stones.

Participated and certified in

- International Chintana Exam (2002
- All India General Knowledge Examination by CHRD (1999 & 2001)
- Senior General Knowledge & Intelligence Test by Central Institute of General Knowledge Learning (2001)
- High School Ramayana Examination by Bharat Sanskriti Pratistana (2000)
- All Rounder Award -2001 @ SSRS Hattiangady.
- Many more.

Interests

Technology, Entrepreneurship, Leadership and Management.

Languages

English(Professional working proficiency)Hindi(Limited working proficiency)Kannada(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Sharath Pandeshwar

Self Explorer

raosharat@gmail.com



11 people have recommended Sharath

"I have had the opportunity to receive training from Sharath in the field of problem solving skills and i had the best experience. i got to learn a lot of skills and techniques in problem solving. he has a very strong hold over the basics of all the concepts in quantitative aptitude. if you are looking to master the art of problem solving then Sharath is the one you should from"

— **Naveen Hegde**, *Student*, *Visvesvaraya Technological University*, worked indirectly for Sharath at QuanTech Origin

"If I have to describe Sharath is one word it would be "Commitment". He has a "never give up" attitude. A go-getter with focus and clear planning. He has an eye for detail which helps him in breaking complex issues into easily solvable modules. And with his Inter personal skills, he gets his team deliver with equal commitment that he shows. As a trainer, he has the ability of keeping his students engaged, entertained and get results with ease. It is my pleasure to be associated with him and I wish him all the very best for all his current/future assignments."

— **Tarun Kohli**, *Freelance Trainer*, *QuanTech Origin*, was with another company when working with Sharath at QuanTech Origin

"Sharath has a great analytical brain and is a shrewd operator. Focused on his Goal and is a workaholic. Sharath exhibits strong interpersonal skills and a unique capacity for empathy. These qualities most notably translate in his ability to motivate a team to care about its project and be invested in the project's success. Sharath is the go-to person for conflict resolution and problem solving; when confusion reigns, he steps in to diffuse tension and induce win-win solution. Though he's never one to draw attention to himself, Sharath's positive attitude and the respect others feel toward him are palpable."

— **Bharat Thangaraj**, *Soft Skills Training Director*, *QuanTech Origin*, reported to Sharath at QuanTech Origin

"Sharath as a colleague is a shining example of professionalism. I am associated with Quantech as a Soft Skills trainer and the first thing I noticed about Sharath is his attention to detail. He is focussed, hard-working and is upfront with his style of working. He is one of the few trainer's I have met who put's his heart and soul into his delivery and content. I have witnessed him tackle even the most stubborn students and get them to be broadminded. It is a real privelege to work with Sharath, and I look foward to a long standing association with Quantech."

— Shweta mathias, Soft Skills Trainer, Vedanta, worked directly with Sharath at QuanTech Origin

"I got an opportunity to work with Sharath for more than three and half years at IBM. He was a very sincere, responsible & meticulous person. It was always a pleasure working with him. Wish you all the best for your future."

— Pradeep Tiwari, Circuit Design, Layout design, IBM, worked directly with Sharath at IBM

"Here are the 10 ways Sharath helped the IBM Blue Expression Toastmasters' Club succeed. 1. Help each other to be right, not wrong. Thru his mentoring and great evaluations Sharath believed that Education and motivation will not only help build the next generation of advanced Toastmasters, it will help them be 'right' in future situations. 2. Look for ways to make new ideas work, not for reasons they won't. New members bring fresh new ideas that merit consideration. Never to dismiss ideas but to spot the nugget of gold, give it a try and if it doesn't pan out, at least making all members feel important and heard. 3. Speak positively about each other and about your organization at every opportunity. Talking positively, representing the Club and making each advancement a reason to brag and wanting to share the excitement with others. 4. Help each other win, and take pride in each others' victories. Everyone in the club needs to help each other excel. Everyone has joined for personal growth, so be proud of each others' successes. Sharath knew, no one wins, unless everyone wins. 5. Compliment often. Praise goes an incredibly long way toward building confidence in communication and leadership. Compliment contributes to a more cohesive and confident team. Sharath always came to the lectern through a positive and motivational introduction. 6. Recognize that the customer is not an interruption to your work, but reason for it. Find ways to bring the new members both into the club and into the speaking schedule so they can immediately start realizing the benefits. 7. Realize that "being right" is irrelevant to good service; the customer's perception is what counts. Guests are golden and should be treated as such. 8. Maintain a positive mental outlook. Doing everything with enthusiasm and good humor; his attitude is contagious. 9. Sacrifice for the good of the team. Sharath always wanted to be the best and also get the best. 10. Have fun. An atmosphere with Sharath is fun and members and those public speaking errors gave members a chance to laugh with, not at the other members. Sharath helped build a culture where everyone accepted the team's goals and were willing to play their part to make them a reality."

— **Dhruti Kapadia Krishnan**, *WW Market Segment Manager - Exceptional Web Experience, IBM*, worked directly with Sharath at Blue Expression Toastmasters Club

"If you are looking for a young and vibrant leader...here he is.... He is one of the very few persons who has a blend of characteristics which makes him unique among others. My interaction with him during the Toastmaster journey has made me realize the potential that he has to become a fantastic Leader. very diligent in his Management, goes to a micro level of planning and ensures a very small activity has been taken care of. As the President of IBM Blue Expression Toastmaster Club, he has taken the club to the highest level that any one could have dreamt off. A meticulous planner, fantastic team player, a very good manager and more important has a very good attitude.. That is Sharath... All the best man.."

— **Sravan Kumar T**, *Delivery Project Executive - IBM (MITS Project -Telcordia), IBM India Pvt. Ltd*, worked directly with Sharath at Blue Expression Toastmasters Club

"It is really marvellous to be so talented and at the same time be so humble and that too at such a young age as Sharath Pandeshwar. His presentation skills match and excel than those with more than 20 years of experience in the industry. He is a hard worker, very truthful, and knows how to inspire people. He is very good at providing constructive criticism to those who look up to him. He has excelled in various roles I have seen him in, including the role of President, Blue Expressions Toastmasters club and the Nexus cricket tournament, the first of its kind in Bangalore. It will be my pleasure to work for him."

— **Hrishikesh Kumar**, *Senior Developer*, *IBM*, worked directly with Sharath at Blue Expression Toastmasters Club

"Sharath is a very dynamic and progressive leader. Under his presidency the Blue Expression Toastmasters Club, grew to new heights winning accolades in both communication and leadership. He works tirelessly towards the progress of the club and its members and has initiated and led many projects. There are leaders who share their vision and let others work. But Sharath does not hesitate to roll up his sleeves and put in the heard work himself. He is a great motivator and visionary and an asset to any team. I wish there were more like him and wish him all the very best for the future."

— **Dr Vikram Venkateswaran**, Market Segment Manager- Healthcare, Life Sciences, Retail and Consumer Products, IBM Global Business Services, worked directly with Sharath at Blue Expression Toastmasters Club

"Sharat is a thorough leader in making! I was amazed with his maturity at his young age. I worked with him in two terms he as VP PR and President of the Blue Expression Toastmasters Club (BETC). As President he lead and demonstrated what is the meaning of 'excellence' not just 'leadership'. His organizing skill till the last point of detail, worth emulating, I appreciate his problem solving & conflict resolution thought process that's very essential while leading a team towards a successul goal and outcome. I thoroughly enjoyed working with Sharat and wish him success and I am sure that he would definitely achieve great strides in near future!"

— **Vittal Kumar A Dhage**, *Asia Pacific Energy Program Manager, IBM*, worked with Sharath at Blue Expression Toastmasters Club

"Sharath, is a good team player. He is a fast learner. He took very less time in understanding the requirements and technologies involved. He did quality deliverable's on-time."

— Chinna Swamy Setty Kapuganti, Technical Lead, IBM, managed Sharath indirectly at IBM-ISL

Contact Sharath on LinkedIn